record hey John I'm enjoying your I'm
enjoying your aliveness right I can feel
your inspiration about about in like I
can see I can feel what you're facing
right like what you're what you're
looking at and how they're talking to
you because they're it seems like it's
calling you almost out of your there's
there's so much happening right now and
they're just so much there's so much a
being exposed to and learning about that
has so much real promise in it for you
know for the work we're doing together
and for the kind of like I was thinking
about it the other day is you know I get
some people who criticize me or
political and I was thinking the other
day I'm not after the French Revolution
or the American Revolution of the
Revolution after something like the
axial revolution that's what I'm yes
that's what a revolutionary I am yes I'm
actually seeing like a little bit yeah
the discipline server networks and some
of the a lot of the other people like
there's this merging thing happening I'm
just seeing a lot of that especially in
this time of Kairos right I'm just so
much so much potential I'm so excited
it's a weird place guard because I've
been tell me people there's something I
still don't know what the proper effect
for what I'm going to say is when I keep
trying it on and that being feels quite
right but you know the crisis has really
increased the relevancy it might work
that's what people are telling me right
and you know Chris and Andrew and I have
been talking about it's you know it's
done these two things I mean you eat
both of these for a Kairos right for a
lot of people it's really exacerbated
Dom aside it's really accelerated a lot
of the features in crisis but for
other people it's shifted their
attention right into the being mode
right and then there's two things there
that are happening one you know with the
discussion with your harness he was sort
of prescient about this when people are
throwing back under their subjectivity
only to find how shallow he is in a lot
of ways oh you know there's that isn't
it in there bubbling and then there's
people who are rediscovering this we
deserve it what wait wait a lot of what
really matters is this ability to
connect other people yeah so I've been
privileged to just be I feel I mean I
feel called to it and there are many
people calling out to me about it and so
this has been just a really intense time
for me but in a very good sense a very
good sense yes that's a myth that's
awesome
and it's going for you it's it's I he's
going really good um I mean for me that
there's not a whole lot that I'm doing
that's that much different I mean I'm
doing stuff with the circling Institute
and you know we're starting we're
starting all kinds of new stuff my wife
is home which is really great and we've
got we brought everything online which
is you know I was pretty hesitant on
doing but like now that we've done it it
actually works remarkably well yeah yeah
and so I'm yeah so I'm having people
like we're doing we just opened we just
opened enrollment for the first circling
training course online and so we're
having people from all over the world
right somebody from Norway just signed
up yeah so it's like it's really
interesting but like when somebody you
know we have the the circling Knights on
on every Thursday and and to have all
these people from you know from all
different time zones even different days
right Australia Norway Russia and like
show up right in our our have a quality
of interest that did that
kind of meets with this kind of quality
of interest or something's been shining
forth to them maybe you don't even have
words for it
however the this medium allows everybody
to actually find each other which is
amazing I mean it's kind of like just
think about it's like what how would we
have ever met Frank yeah if it wasn't
for this yeah yeah absolutely so so yeah
I think it's this this time for me has
been he's it's just it's one thing is
I've also just moved to Alameda which is
like a little island right right by San
Francisco and and I've just been able to
just I've gone on tons of walks and I
live in this old historical neighborhood
and as I'm walking along there's a
Alameda is one of those places that you
can't get it just by going to it once
like it reveals itself to you and I'm
getting and it's it's turning out to be
the perfect place for Brianna died I was
like yeah so it's like on one level for
me personally there's a there's a
there's like a simplicity and almost a
meditativeness right like inwardly but
outwardly and all these other levels I'm
like more I'm reading more crazy stuff
and like into these different ways and
doing all these experiments and my you
know I'm exploring in pushing edges on a
on a pretty profound level that's right
at the same time very privileged you are
I am you know our lives have a structure
to them that has a resiliency to though
other people are not so fortunate right
in both both physically and
psychologically they're hammered really
really hard or they go to plant some of
those people
and trying to reach out and provide some
kind of support and help for them has
been something I've been trying to
address as you know I've been doing a
free online meditation and contemplation
class and of course and I'm getting the
feedback I'm getting is that people are
finding it very helpful very relevant
but I am very cognizant of the fact like
I said that this is a very strange time
the system is being very radically
destabilized that always brings with a
tremendous suffering and distress right
you know but it also brings both
individually as you and I are finding
but I think even more important
collectively as I think you're both
seated within this new this new you know
this almost maelstrom of amazing
conversations and community building
that's occurring but it's Amanda's
opportunity for people to and so Neil
for both of those reasons for both of
them together almost like stereoscopic
vision I feel a tremendous urgency right
now there's tremendous urgency oh yeah
totally yeah there is an urgency and
there's a way there's a way to
communicate I could just get this sense
that there's there's when I look at like
right the rebel wisdom community and I
look at all the people watching our
videos and all like you're the discord
server all the things that we're talking
about I just like okay where where were
those people before all this right like
there's a there's a way where there's a
certain kind of quality of conversation
or an openness to a certain in anyway I
like about it it's a it's a mode that's
distinct for me because it's not just
like as I think you would talk about
it's not just the embodiment authentic
relating right mode but it's but it's
but it's also and it's not just the kind
of academic or intellectual mode but
there it's it seems to be attracting
people who have a have a sense for both
of
right yes yes it want to hang and like
have a sense of being interested and
drawn to that yes yeah yeah yeah yeah
they're not academics and they're not
just into the importance because you
know you know more than anybody else and
I've experienced the importance of that
kind of interpersonal intimacy and that
means a lot for me right the
interpersonal intimacy you get in
certain things but these people they're
they're they're they're they're they're
connoisseurs of intelligibility they
write they want to taste they want it
right and so yeah and and so they're the
people that you know I'm trying but we
you know this is a group project right
that we're trying to work I've just said
what I'm putting a lot of my work into
and I know you are new mm-hmm I'm trying
to you know craft you know double vision
looking back to the best historical
templates we are looking I the current
cutting-edge emerging practices and PW
practices craft recycler technology have
died elected to a 4d logos so that
people know what it is like to taste by
knowing right you know you know the
serious play with intelligibility and
what does that mean you know not just as
cognitive agent but what does it mean as
an existential being that's that's why
that community it is the community that
I'm especially trying to reach and so
generally I find the people that are
sort of purely academically oriented or
purely theoretically oriented they sort
of know what's this and where's the
theory and I say well lots of theory
elsewhere this is something else I'm
trying to do here yeah the people
there's other people you probably do
this a lot yeah well I just want to feel
close to other people is that great yes
but but you know we need more than that
right now right we need more than that
right now the nd we need a lot more
right now so yeah the community but the
people that you are identifying as
a population that's the people that are
at most because most concern to help to
afford to address and to listen to and
to listen to right right absolutely and
the the thing that you've been talking
about lately I've heard you talk about
lately is these these two distinctions
are you bringing together a couple of
things I wanted to highlight them and
pin them because it gets to what you
wanted to talk about in the beginning I
think which I want to circle back around
to which is this way that of looking at
right this that we're we're the two you
could say bottom-up and top-down right
kind of meet and bleed into each other
and point to each other right this sense
of this sense of like being was like
being with somebody and there's such
this and in the same time there's
there's in dialogue owes there's there's
reaching into and being reached by the
inexhaustible right the beyond this the
the more Ness right and it's in when you
swinney when you put it like that right
it's interesting because I thought I had
a felt sense of exactly I thought that
was that the perfect two things to bring
it together in that way because I've
noticed this sense in what in fact I
just uploaded a circle I did a training
circle I did on to my channel which was
kind of watching going deep into this
getting getting this person's essence
right but it it just bled into these
kind of really big insights right and
they were it was almost like you could
talk about the most like difficult
personal thing for her
and what's opening up around that to
like the nature of the universe at the
same time it's like at some point they
just like they became figure-ground and
then they just started to bleed into
each other like I think that's exactly
right
about this so I was you know I'm not
very happy with like I'm sorry with the
term but I don't and you know the some
of the people on the discord server was
saying you get it come up with a better
term but I mean it was a circle around
this idea that I was playing with a
trying serious play with or trying to
give a secular version of soul yeah as I
wanted one of the things I'm really
working on right now is there's going to
be talking about a rebel wisdom I'm
trying to bring out of the three mottos
the idea you know that the mind is
monolithic it has one way of knowing
propositional knowing right the idea
that the mind is ultimately monologic
and that reason is monologic rather than
but all the accumulating evidence and
practice is showing there it's
ultimately biological with nature pray
and then the mind is minded phasic
there's one state of consciousness you
should be in and only that's didn't
consciousness gives access to reality
and all the other ones are just aberrant
and trying to break out of all of that
in a significant fashion and so what
Descartes did was he tied the notion of
soul and self he first of all fuse them
together and you know he tied that to
that that you know that inner point of
subjectivity that is the center of the
model that triple motto mind about three
dimensions of being sort of monolithic
monophasic right mano monologic when i'm
trying i'm thinking well what if we what
do we try to read so there's this
wonderful word that Kari uses in his
book on Agustin and the invention of the
inner self he says the Woody actually
wants is the Latin word inventio which
means both to discover and to invent so
things that we see as the economist yeah
how relevant that is to dialogo say
discovering and inventing right right
right I said to Paul I wanted to try and
reinvent yo soul to break out of that
break that triple one ISM right the
bottom of mine and I wanted to redo it
in terms of its phenomenology and
functionality and that's why I was
trying to get at yeah I
oh I was trying to get at something like
analogous
jeez I hope I'm not offending people I
really don't want you to call didn't
they defend something analogous to
worship like what reverence is because
this is part of what we you and I are
talking about with the via logos right
the reverence for the logos when it
emerges I was trying to get out ok well
the soul was the was the Faculty of
worship what does that mean well know
normally that means you're sort of
praising and I thought well well what if
what if right what if it was it's the
faculty that mediates between the
mourners and the section Asst yeah right
your soul is that which right so your
spirit is that which affords you self
transcendence but your soul is that is
the locust right it's the horizon
intelligibility the Janus space thing
that is simultaneously synoptic Lee
right now like stereoscopic vision like
Sybil lawn joining together right it's
what seeing together symbol on together
the more nests and the suchness that's
the soul and then just like you were
saying yeah you've picked up on this
perfectly you know I've been targeted
Chris about you know that what you the
soulful nature of dia logos right that
what happens is you get if the if the
logos is present you get a sense
simultaneously of the more nespresso
nation but the section is of
individuation and they're the
missionaries are just resonating with
each other and there's ask there's this
faculty that comes into into awareness
yeah so I'm trying to reinvent you right
so the you know there's something
soulful about you know deal logos and
what it does is it picks up on our that
part of us that is active symbol long
between the morning and the section is
apology really like that sort of a
secular version at all yeah so I'm just
trying to I mean you see you know what
I'm doing of course I'm trying to bring
as much of the Theor gia yeah the OREA
right here as possible right so the
thing you just said
yeah totally yeah - because like you
know it picks up on you know what Chris
and I are talking about in the chapter
you know that the sensibility
transcendence is really picking up on
the sections of another person you every
participant is soulful and that they are
there the salon by the stairs confusion
and symbol are yes'm the furnace and the
such list and that's part of the
phenomenology and the vanity of being in
via logos right right yeah yeah totally
and there's this is some TV anamnesis
Satya
this is to remember the soul and yet can
break out of the Cartesian monism right
that not the - of a mine monolithic you
know monophasic monological mind and
yeah no no mine is mine for
problem-solving in cognition soul is
this existential mediating function hmm
yeah totally
and this in this you know bringing it
bringing that back into just you know
I'm taking all this and I'm just
bringing this back into this sense of
what you're talking about which is this
this help me out with this but what you
were talking about this this sense of
speaking or thinking in this yeah so I
mean when people sometimes ask me to
give them the elevator pitch for
dialectic the dialectic is the psycho
technology diello dose is the process
you participate I say yes dialectic but
you can only participate in deal though
the right very similar to the
distinction between dialectic and
dialogue yeah so but the the so the
elevator pitch I give to people is
you've realized the Ilocos when you're
both getting to a place that neither one
of you
could have gotten to on your own all
right and people people have an
intuitive sense of what that means so
it's great word yeah yeah I don't know
what that means
then they generate all I get there and
then that that's a really good opening
to the elevator pitch huh yeah but then
I was thinking I was thinking okay but
let's get a little bit more fine-grained
let's you know little it's you know a
finer resolution and I was thinking
about well part of what that means not
comprehensively but part of what it
means is I've been noticing that when
I'm practicing it with you guys with
other people that I'm doing this weird
thing normally you know people think and
then they speak right and then they
listen and then they think there's a
little bit of online yeah but there's
something different when I start
practicing dialectic and yellow those
starts - yeah yeah which is I find that
I'm thinking by speaking and like
looking right speaking yeah so that's
like I'm trying to get there's a felt
sense and I felt difference in
functionality between being monolith
well being monologic you're talking in
your head and then when I put it out and
I'm speaking to you and I'm getting your
online feedback even just really yeah
you know in intuitively an implicit
learning then what happens is right I'm
noticing that the act of articulating my
words in your presence is actually you
know it's articulating in a sense of
action it's articulating my thinking my
thinking is coming into shape as I'm
speaking right like I can't tell you
what my thought is going to be yeah
until the speaking has has sort of
finished a cycle of resonance yeah yeah
yeah or interesting it so that reminded
me of something and you and I talked
about this before I try to think about
where else have I felt that kind of
thing and it reminded me of
when teaching is going well I'm learning
as I'm teaching right and I'm itching
because I'm learning teaching yes I
don't my learning is have done and then
I'm teaching
on another just learning I'm Samba
tediously teaching and learning as I'm
teaching like the act of teaching is
opening things up yeah yeah there's the
teaching and the learning are happening
in this great parallel and
interpenetrating fashion yeah yeah
that's not just an analogy or a
similarity think of Socrates both of
those are happening like the thinking by
speaking and teaching by learning are
also like this yes right right right
totally in this there's also this sense
in which yeah I mean I'm just feet I'm
seeing visually all the you know the
normativity right that is that that
that's that's being that's being this
you know using a hands and me to like
hands back and forth like this sense of
like finding each other right Co finding
each other shaping each other and it in
that as that normativity starts to catch
hold right you start to break in to
start saying stuff that you didn't know
about like what it but it's but it's
wedded in some way to the other person's
listening in that particular way where
it's like the speaking it's almost like
it's almost like it's as if it's as if
you know my my words are more like the
thought and the other person is more
like the the the the representation of
that thought like realizing itself back
around right because there is that
partner there is that part of listening
which is really interesting to think
about listening like this relationship
between
sitting in thought right because did you
get this book oh yeah totally
yeah I've read that like five ten times
yeah that's a really good book yes but
one of the things that she actually goes
into a lot is that well she talks about
how and this is what had me start
thinking about it is how listening is
really we think about listening usually
like being an empty vessel and sound
comes in and we received no it's
synonymous with interpretation and in
some way right when you talk and I
listen if I'm listening right and I
start thinking is the moment I stopped
listening yeah right and that what that
I think that shows this shows how wedded
listening and thinking really are yeah
so I think of listening more and more
like you know like the internalization
that is needed for genuine sensibility
transcendence it dawn right sense like
alright this is this is again like part
of me when I'm listening what I'm doing
is trying to tailor my attention my
memory my receptivity to your suchness
yeah right so like I feel like oh here's
a such anise and then behind me and
behind you sort of yeah around us all
right is the morning yeah right and so
right I try to speak the bornus and I
try to listen to your suchness does that
make any sense yeah and I listen to your
suchness yeah yeah exactly exactly
exactly it's almost like we're my it's
like in some way like right now I'm kind
of I can hear it I'm like listening for
what's being thought and then you said
yes yes exactly right so there's that
sense in which there's that sense in
which I
I listened for what - and then I speak
it right and then and then you respond
in that sense and there's something that
like what's the feet like then then that
goes back over here what does that do
right so I'm wondering about if that's
kind of the normativity or the this is
honing into the sweet spot like feeling
into oh and here's that thing about like
okay that sense in which I've noticed
this - of where you're you're you're
listening to somebody and then something
happens any it breaks the flow in its
agitated right but I didn't know like I
didn't know that there was a flow I was
tuned into until it broke right so
there's that sense of like that sense of
like on some level we both are finding
out what we're tuning into right and
that seems to be that sense of like is
that what you and Chris have been
talking about the Geist right yeah I
think the Geist is the soul DMO goes
away right so what you're getting is
like so it reminds me of Fisher's notion
of wonder if wonder is you're on the
horizon of intelligibility what the
logos is the logos is right it's the
it's the it's the presence of the
horizon intelligibility it's the morning
eligibility shining into section Asst
what's particularly spoken in in a non
repeatable fashion right if we try to
make this in any way formulaic we'll
lose it yeah whose is it always has to
be jazz you know I was trying to think
about okay well again what's that doing
well we are we're not just talking about
the logo spam we're embodying it we're
instantiating it but then we're also
right we're also it is also symbol on
it's also of finding us you know the way
Brut being is disclosing itself through
as I keep saying you know the
logos defines us to the on two logos
yeah and and so for me that moment of
the third factor like you said that
we're we're I mean part of it is you
know part of it is you know cognitive
science part of it is what's happening
is you and I are figuring out right how
to get into the zone of proximal
development you're putting enough
challenge on me that I have to stay
really engaged yeah like if I start to
break out of authenticity
Junya you said in the error signal
really rapidly even by they're like you
your brows will go down slightly you're
yeah yeah you know it's tightly coupled
what you so we're getting all the flow
stuff but we're doing more than that
right because there's also this there's
and this is this is what I'm trying to
talk what we're trying to right we're
trying to trying to give birth right
it's a it's a deeper conception of
consecutive conception but we're trying
to give birth like yeah this flow itself
is it that's that's not the goal the
flow it's great but the flow is
ultimately the affordance of a
reorientation of faith coming into right
relationship with other people right
relationship with ourselves right
relationship with being right totally
coming into right relationship yes like
this cope it's both are reveal yeah it's
a revealing right and a coming to being
revealed it's it's it's yes exactly like
about that it's like almost it's almost
like unbootable to trying to reinvent
you soul I don't reinvent your faith in
terms of the sense of faithfulness you
know Jordan and I been talking about
this think about how you're faithful to
Breanna it doesn't mean that you have a
fun you don't have a set of dogmas you
don't know I know have you thin it I
have my set of unchangeable beliefs
about you right that's not what it means
that that's that's that's disaster if
you get it it means I am I have coupled
the emergence of me to the emergence of
you so that those will all
the affording and constraining each
other and so that's faithfulness right
yeah that's that's faithfulness and so
that's a continuity of contact yes that
right the continuity of contact so
thinking about right relationship as
evolving adaptive continuity of contact
not as you said as any closure or
doctorate ization right right right
you know I'm cut I've been I've been I
by the way I really have enjoyed the
psychologist that you've had on a couple
of times I think also yeah that last
that last one yeah that last one where
he laid out he brought up the picture
and laid out the model justify that so
so there's something about this thing
about being a forum right like the world
be of being a forum in which I I am on
trial all right on some level for
justification right so I want to just
kind of like think about this right
but that's so Socratic right that what
we're doing we and this this is what
Christopher Moore argue so brilliantly
in his book and you see it also in
Gonzalez book right yeah that we only
really know ourselves as persons when we
enter the field of justification yeah
right would you not feel the blade it's
not the field of accusation that's how
we mess these things up I feel the
justification and that you know Greg on
leaks and I are happy I'm gonna have him
on regularly like once a month I really
want you to talk to him right
I think it'd be really amazing yeah but
Moore's idea right that I only it's a
highly it's not introspection it's not
even reflection it's not going over my
autobiography well how I know myself as
a person is only
seeing how I enter into you and admit
myself within the arena of justification
so self-examination and the examination
of the ways of life to which I'm willing
to commit myself yes and how they are a
fine to the ways of speaking to which
I'm willing to commit myself that's the
only way of knowing yourself as a person
yeah yeah absolutely
yeah absolutely yeah I mean I've thought
about this a bunch of times if like if
you took an infant you're right you put
it in a digital I like an island and it
just grew up like what would it would
say it could speak right which you
couldn't but like what when he asked it
about itself what would it say it
reminds me of Einstein's things even if
lions could speak this would be this
would be a biological human being
presumably in some fashion yeah I mean I
say this really carefully and I don't
want to fall into some sort of easy
moral error or be subject to
unreasonable moral judgment I don't it
wouldn't speak as a person yeah because
a person because it hasn't had to take
response network as an egg to take
responsibility for you know tending the
load up yes yes so there's something
about so there's something about right
if we look at like the logos and the
conditions of do logos right like at one
level
what we're talking about is like the vet
it's like what you're saying is is the
very stuff of which our development
develops through right it's like it's on
some level it's like this is some of the
stuff is just site this is like don't
developmental psychology and a lot in a
lot of ways however I think the thing
that were for whatever reason right this
kind of sense about what's possible in
relating this way as a spiritual
practice right has not really I've not
seen it right I've not seen it in the
set in the way that we're talking about
I think that there was like is the sir
you know the Platonic dialogues right
but the you know most of that is just I
mean most of that stuff has just been
studied
you know systematized and studied and oh
yeah academic settings but the sense of
and I just I hate wonder to what you
think about this blind spot where when
gonzales starts to talk about like no
you got it you can't just interpret the
content of the dialogue you gotta like
look at the it's yeah it's the process
itself is is is is kind of in so many
ways is is is the place where you find
out where the thing really is it's the
point of the dialogue yeah use elbow
wrap a argues yeah more argues like this
is this isn't like this is complaint
like you know pay attention pay
attention there's this growing
convergence about you know how much the
drama is doing as much work as the
arguments right in fact times the
arguments are just bring you to the
suppori a-- where all of a sudden none
of the answers right that that classic
right ironic like Socratic thing is
where everything just falls apart and
then and then then everyone's really
like ecstatic right at the end and there
and people and there's all this points
out there but when you get is you get
the people who are often the combative
interlocutors with somebody saying but i
want my son's to come and spend time
with you doesn't get a way of life a
right relationship
yeah the logos of its eligibility has
been disclosed to them and they have an
intuitive sense that being around
somebody who can regularly bring this
practice about is going to be beneficial
to their kids in a way in which you know
the over techno is a ssin of the sofas
and their see the obvious of common
sense won't educate because think about
what you've said a few minutes ago
you know this stuff we're talking about
here this is the guts of personhood
yes spirituality and reverence are about
you know accessing and act
reading in celebrating and accelerating
personhood that's what it's about
yes it's a it got me thinking about also
what you just said a minute ago sorry
there's you're setting up firecrackers
in my mind right but fireworks
about the normativity and I was thinking
that when we want to turn this as we're
doing it all naturally I'm trying to
think about okay but to teach to model
yeah I thought you know I don't think
it's happenstance that the dialogues are
about virtues
yeah because virtue is the place where
the more nests and the suchness where
the intelligibility and the normativity
are coming together it's like that's the
top because it's both yes by its very
nature it has to be shareable with
others but it has to be personally
relevant to you within your with your
ability as a person to commit yourself
to to the forum of justification right
the logos brings together
intelligibility and commitment so the
main topics of philosophy ax should be
the virtues it should be like what is
love but I'm gonna expand the virtues
what is meaning what is wonder what is
beauty like all of these that's like so
it's not going to be like pure
philosophy where women talk about the
nature of cause
but it's gonna be it's there is it's not
happenstance yet the topics are the
virtues and this is where your intuition
about how lecto do like if you do lectio
Divina in a grill right we'll we'll kind
of naturally kind of just give rise most
likely to dialogue those readers want to
see this they can go to my channel and
the lesson I gave yesterday on how to
practice like together you know it
should not be practiced until it's an
advanced technique you should go through
you should have at least an introductory
course the meditation contemplation
before you practice Lexi oh but let's
take that for granted
yeah I think the point about Lexi o as a
bridging practice
is because on one side it reaches into
the prepositions because you're reading
but yeah but part of the Lexi Oh is you
set yourself to listen right yeah yeah
you set yourself with an intention to
resonate with it and to read for
transformation not to read for
information yeah recite and you resonate
and then you you you're open to what
grabs your attention
yeah and they internalize it and then
you enact it imaginal ii not in your
imagination space introspectively you
like projective leon the world and then
what would if you like to live this way
right when do you like to actually
commit myself to this sort of an
existential ethics then what's disclosed
about me if i were to live this way and
correspondingly here's the normativity
what would be demanded from me in order
to conformity without realization yeah
and then the idea is you know so i'm
teaching people how to do it
individually but on the discord server
talk about yeah but we want to do this
community and that that's so so
important right yeah yeah so what i see
it happening is one person would do the
rest citation and then everybody has
their own individual moments where
they're doing going through this process
you know yeah but then they start to
share all the different perspective
titles and participatory transformations
yeah aren't that they're getting an
inkling of that they are getting a taste
connoisseur of how to aspire and then i
think that will naturally start to lead
into right in india logos because you
know that the sacred prose the sacred
poetry in the centered prose and should
we both by the way one of each because
you want you want them to talk to each
other so that they can talk to you right
right ah but that that right that's
going to naturally that you're going to
give you the Vleck co is going to reach
back because you do it after you've done
a meditative or contemplative practice
or a prior to practice and it's going to
reach back to that that's going to
afford you resonating with the
propositions but moving into the
perspective of a participatory and then
that's gonna when you're doing it in
group it's gonna naturally fee you know
goes because right what you're training
is
really virtue that is needed for
aspiration right and transformation
which is the virtue of reverence Paul
Woodruff idea that rather kind of
relevance realization yeah properly put
you into right relationship to what aw
and Wonder disclosed you as possible
yeah in fact I'm wondering about like so
now I'm just flashing back to like all
the moments that were like that like
body memory but like things and this is
like some of the most immediate ones
right are it has me wonder is this is
the thing that is becomes present in we
in a certain sense see right win this
win the suchness and the more nests
Flake are you know we're foreground they
wants to become for Graham Beca and they
do this switching at some point they
bleed into each other words just
animating I'm wondering is like it's
kinda like when I think about that sense
of being deeply moved by somebody right
yes that sense of being in reverence
right like this coat like that
I'm disclosed in their in disclosing
them right in that there's that sense of
like reverence where they're they're
such this is just a lie I guess it's
usually I'm wondering about on another
level if that's like almost like we're
in the direct to the the the the virtue
that I'm actually seeing a virtue in you
right that is that in some way is is
like the I don't know if there was an F
like if there was an essential if it was
a sound right like is that is that the
the sense of where the the virtue were
the the suchness and the more nest meat
if that's the point where the virtue the
sound of the virtue goes I think that's
exactly right you know it's so Murdock
talks about this in the sovereignty of
the good and that's where John Wright
got the notion of sensibility
transcendence
so we windows to like the virtue I think
is the bird I think it's a virtue I
would say this missus as she says it I
now seeing you in a virtuous manner she
says that the the primary act of virtue
on ethics is proper attention attending
two things justly is the core mr. Feeny
that that's the core virtuous act for
her right because I'm fifty that's where
that that's that's where that's that
Nexus upon you when you do and I think
attending two things justly is a part of
what reverence means right and again
this is the secular or overlap with what
worship used to me worship is to me
being sort of a sympathetic Tony to God
and I don't mean anything insulting to
the people that I know who I think you
know but but I'm talking about a
caricature that has become prevalent in
popular culture yeah he part on has made
fun of it like in the meaning of life
right oh god you're so but the gate
don't burn us you know all that all that
kind of crap right but what I think was
what was going on in what I guess for
lack of a better term I don't like this
adjective but authentic worship right
what was exactly that it's the sense of
you know there is a just attention that
carries with that I should have to God
and that brings with it a sense of
reverence that I add to into that virtue
of maintaining the right relationship
with that which continually can be a
fount of intelligibility for me through
all and wonder that's see that's why I'm
trying to unpack you yeah yeah
absolutely
and there's that that sense in which the
virtue in which I'm seeing let's say
like let's just say I see something
about you in your life right in that
moment and something shined foot and
just moves me yes yes yes member the
suppose you he says you move from and we
talk about this the beauty right yeah
the physical beauty right to the beauty
of virtue right yes
exactly so I think that's exactly right
when that and that that moment sort of
crystallizes right and there's that and
it's like it's really interesting
because at those moments I noticed that
the that it's so there is a silence
that's so much at ease in in in
partaking right when you're talking
about virtue right people are right
there what they're doing is move from
reflecting to participating in its
exemplification yeah yeah you and I you
think about how you're doing this I know
you're doing it I'm doing it
yeah we're trying to notice in what
we're doing the very virtue that we're
also talking about this is what I mean
by thinking and by speaking the speaking
right is you know what you're doing is
you're constantly moving between
reflection and exemplification and you
know that's why I can't think
independently of speaking it the speech
is where I engage in the mirroring of
the exemplification right right when we
connect it's like ah and so I can
continually go back and forth between
right and this is what you should be
doing in good phenomenology right here's
my conceptualization here's my
articulation here's my attempt to speak
the intelligibility the logos but here
is my connectedness here's my
participants an exemplification of the
very thing and virtues do that for us
yes virtue is the topic that not only
commits us to aspiration and also
constantly toggles us which eats each
reflective speech and speech that
exemplifies and in acts right totally Oh
interesting
it's like it's interesting because the
virtues themselves right if it makes
sense to call it themselves right yeah
it seems like virtues are those things
that like it's a little
they they're starting to occur to be a
little bit like light you know how light
has it it it it withdrawals in its
complete disclosure great point about
you know the virtues and and that Plato
makes very clear and highly makes its
really clear and the question of beauty
the things like beauty should be good
the ability to relate to beauty properly
should be considered a via pert you as
well yeah right but but but but think
about think about what what constantly
happens as you pointed out in the
dialogues we can't get a definition of
courage we get is an ongoing right
relationship to it not just in fought in
reflection but because we're
exemplifying it it's also calling us to
commitment it's calling us to the space
of justification I mean it's it's
calling us to transfer Meishan you can't
get a definition but we can't rely on
just our untutored intuitions about
courage either you have to enter into
this process and all we get is an
ongoing right relationship virtues are
also the thing that steer us between
definition and into and untutored
intuition totally it's almost like
there's a sense of getting a sense of it
like tuning an instrument like two
pictures right it's a tone us yeah you
have to say that your your Heidegger
incarnate yeah for the longest time
no I when I first read that I only got
it sort of conceptually yeah and then I
sort of got it phenomenologically but
you know and I hope this is the right
adjective yeah I'm getting it
spiritually I'm getting with attitude
yeah oh it's bound up with total
hopefulness and faithfulness and virtue
in the way we're talking about you right
totally
what did you think like when you think
about a tune meant it's it's that thing
where it's it's interesting a tune is
one of those things where it's like you
it's like it's kind of little bit like
you know
queeny's talks about time right you know
if you don't ask me I know exactly what
time is right so the moment you ask me
either
I realize it's I have no fuck I have no
idea it's I'm perplexed right there's a
sense with the two met that it's kind of
like that like what if you don't ask me
what a tune mitt is I know exactly what
it is
because it's but there's something about
when you go what is a tournament but
there is this quality of I guess
thinking about this like with the the
sense of right thinking about about
tears and grief right and and and like
often times what I see
is is that when someone's in grief right
for example it's like and they're alone
there's a way in which it's not totally
grief until they speak about it and in
portray please I want I want it I want
to slow down I want to treat this with
proper reverence but there was I was
doing a medal one of the moms like the
live classes and somebody brought up and
I won't disclose their neighbors and
what don't want to trespass on privacy
but I do want to I do want to express
yeah you know gratitude for their
honesty they're great they brought up
that they were in grief and they were
asking well how can the practice help
and part of what I try to articulate is
how grief has to be shared not because
there's a solution grief is a permanent
aporia right with these our language
here but what we're after is the way in
which brief deeply humanizes is in the
sense of puts us into that soulful phase
a note right ass because I was talking
about I related the story of I'll
quickly do it here because I think it's
helpful so a woman comes to the Buddha
and her son is died this is this is why
I love this those things have moved me
yeah and she says to the Buddha you know
resurrect him because I love my son I'm
in such deep breathing and she says no
always refused to do mirror and she
keeps asking and she's persistent so
then he turns or he said okay I will do
it but first you have to do one thing
you have to go into the city and you
have to go to a household and find a
host
mustardseed oh great that's easy wait
one thing it has to be that nobody in
the household has tasted death or grief
yeah yeah so she goes and she knocks on
the door and the ebony mustardseed of
just one oh yeah sure but oh but does
anybody please the death oh yes of
course and that she goes from house the
house the house the house and then she
goes oh back to the Buddha and she says
thank you now I go right and I said what
we what we need is there's no answer in
the proposition what we need is we need
to felt that we're we need to help see I
thought about you when I was saying we
need to felt either feel seen you need
to feel heard and we need to be deeply
in touch with you know that grief is one
of I I don't want anybody to go through
grief I'm not some sort of masochist but
there is that thing that humanizes us
more than growing through grief yeah one
of the wisest people I met at my life
perhaps wisest I've met a person he gave
me this advice he said don't get
involved with anybody like he met deeply
friendship or romantically who hasn't
experienced grief he let that like it's
the opposite of the Buddhist Oriya they
will they will not have sunk moves into
the depths of their humanity and then
have not gone through grief totally
exactly that it's it's it's what will
ultimately the only thing it's to be
connected with people who can't afford
us the only way we can go through grief
which is to grow into yeah somebody else
yeah looting in another world because
that's what we have to go okay somebody
when we lose or somebody dies our world
is destroyed and we have to grow into
another person in another world that's
the only way and that process that puts
us in touch yeah absolutely and then
it's kind of like when we go through
that there's a sense in which when we
sit with another because I was thinking
about this back to this thing about with
the tune meant right that it's and I
think this is kind of also
were you know India logo says we we a -
we are tuned by and a tune in to write
these virtues right right yes there's a
there's a way in which when I'm for
example when I'm sitting with somebody
with grief there's so like like there's
a tuning to them there's like kind of
feeling what it would be like to be them
and like sensing it and like tuning into
it but no no this is here's the here's
the thing yeah here's the thing where I
think that the practice of what it's
like
dialo goes the machinery and exercises
is that like I think real attunement
though is like yeah I'm a tuning into
your grief right but I'm also a tuning
into something that you may not be able
to be have access in because your grief
right which is I can tune into qualities
of being I can be attuned with you and
your grief so I'm like I can tune into
you and I can tune into your future
I can I can tune into these and that's
like sitting with a white person right
like that's good that that that speaks
that puts into speech sort of an image I
had of when people they eat the feel
seen and heard but your presence I was
thinking about like what can happen is
people are cramped in their green for a
long time you ask me what's different
now and I said I'm not stuck yeah
remember that yeah yeah what happens if
you open up this space
you don't say anything to people yeah
there's nothing to say yeah you can say
that won't be useless absolutely useless
right well what you do is what you just
articulated it is you open up a space
you scaffold access right and so that
they're they're not they're not cramped
in their grief they still have to unfold
it on a packet there's no way there's
nothing this is a way that wise person
said to me he said there's nothing you
can do about grief except go through it
yeah right but what you do is like when
you with somebody and they felt they
feel seed and heard and then you can you
can like again
if you try and do this in any kind of
manipulative fashion its it turns in
device very very quickly yeah totally do
it if you can do it virtuously you can
open up a space so the person you're not
alleviating their grief what you're
doing is preventing the grief from being
cramped into a kind of stuckness yeah
yes yes yes absolutely and there's a way
that you think about it so you know this
is kind of like just imagine grieving
right with Yoda right there's a sense
where he would not look away he would
not diminish he wouldn't deny he in fact
if anything he'll he'll uncomfortably
reflect back to you how painful it is in
all of its dimensions maybe even more
than you're feeling it but at the same
time he's also probably revealing
eternity to you at everything beyond it
right there's that sense of I really
like this sense of attunement and a
tuning in to things and what's happening
in and also with speech and thought
right it's like hearing great all these
things kind of working together and this
sense of you know there's always that
sense of where you know when the Geist
that we've been tuning into right at
some point shows up as the thing is is
is the thing that was always already the
case yes like there's that that quality
of at some point the we always already
becomes like think of what you're inside
of yeah but this is the Platonic insight
about that that feature of the logos
which you know one of the things I love
about you is you always you always give
voice to that you always call us back to
this and you always wonder about this
ruling I me to do irreverence about it
but think about this was Plato's point
and this is part of the anamnesis idea
right is that virtues have to have that
to them to some degree if you had no and
this was part of Aristotle's worry about
education and why you have to have the
right products but if you have know if
you have if you do not have the power if
you do not have the potency in act
yes right the actual potentiality
activated the power right you don't have
some honesty I can't teach you honesty
right I'll ant right if you don't have
that commitment
if you don't sense its normativity yeah
like there's no way yeah yeah you maybe
think about the grief here maybe Liam
Socrates in you may be cramped you may
be sack right and I can afford you
unfolding that but if there's a sense in
which its enemies is it like you always
had to have some genuine virtue of
honesty that's why you can exemplify it
yes of practice and then be called by
the virtue is where we where we can
really pick up on we could really have a
new this work very strongly enough where
we can personalize that feature that you
keep putting your finger on that we we
discover you have to discover something
yeah already some degree prep present
and affording us I come to discover what
honesty is only because there was some
honesty in you and I already there a 40
yeah the discussion of honest right
right
how interesting yeah so interesting I
just want to kind of hang with that for
a second
you had that sense of that that sense of
that always already right it is what it
reveals itself right there is a sense
like this is where the like things like
faith and trust seem to seem to be
something just indigenous to it right
there's something about there's
something about like there's something
about like finding fight like that
there's that experience of like you know
you just think you're fucked right you
just think it's the ailing you're in
some kind of catastrophic thing and it's
like you're just convinced it's all
gonna fall apart and then at some point
something happens or you realize there's
somebody says something and all of a
sudden you're like OOP like oh it's it's
fine in fact it was fine the whole time
right and there's that sense in which
like where it's been okay in this way
that I didn't I couldn't produce it like
out of nothing
there's something about that recognition
of the background he's already always
already been in there eaten it I could
like that I could it could be concealed
from me and it still operates in
organized the experience and be present
without like in a certain sense without
me yes right even maybe in spite of me
on some level right that there's there's
some kind of sense of because there's
that quality there's that quality of
like I'm thinking about went whittling
the quality of awareness or being or the
felt sense of what Wincott talks about
the the holding environment yeah yeah
cuz that's some level I think I think
that there's a way in which we're always
tuned into a certain way because we're
always inside of something we're always
in the world so there's always this the
way it seems or it is and there
a quality of like holded this gray and
so there's something about there's
something about these kinds of dialogues
right then are so encouraging right yes
right totally it's like they're
encouraging and I think the faith part
is this kind of recognition of oh god
there's just like there's something
there's an intelligibility that's beyond
me it's operating through me and I can
it can be concealed for me and it still
goes right and then when I find out if
there's something about that just goes
really deep in the nervous system
genders it encourages us I think that
interests us they trust us it brings us
into you know a kind of faithfulness
I think that's deeply right notice again
come back to the you know the point
Gonzalez makes you know this how
the way you could be mistaken about this
with that which was that which I
discover about was which was always
there
you could mistake that with the the
untutored intuition of common sense you
could at all it's just my intuition that
it's not that it's not that or you could
mistake that with oh well there's a
there's a there's a definition that
captures this yeah and I can then hold
on to it by holding on to the definition
you can hold faith is not holding on to
a Dogma or a definition nor is it just
your untutored intuition see how both of
those right mistakes of we're trying to
talk about something that's neither just
intuition nor formalized possession
right because yes you said you
discovered that it was always there but
it's also a real discovery that's why I
like this term inventio yes I guess yes
it's right I mean an adventure right
right right and it's not your possession
you know right so but here's a virtue
here of getting that sensitivity to that
sweet spot here's nearly between the
skillet and Charybdis of you know the
obvious of my intuition and common sense
or you know the
self evidence of this formal definition
its capture everything completely and
consistently define right no it's you're
trying to find and that's what you see
the dialogue to do it again and again
and again sail between those sail
between those sail between those right
totally infected knit and thence finding
in finding that you like that sense I
know Jordan does this a lot right where
help you like feel like he'll recognize
oh wait a minute I realized when like
this maybe he got too fast or something
like that like when it went off that I
was tuning in there was a flow that was
happening that didn't reveal itself
until it was gone right and there is
that that sense of finding all of our
attention being oriented to something
right I think so
I think it's it's all of these things
it's a sense of an emerging right
relationship the connectedness the sense
that we are being we are being educated
in the sense of a juice draw forth yeah
I'm cramping and unfolding of virtue but
but that virtue is always bound up with
this necessarily it the way in which
right thus speaking that is thinking of
the logos is becoming beautiful to us
and drawing us and saying look you don't
oh yes this is what this is what I could
be yeah this is this is well that's that
bet there's different there's like their
home you netic circle yeah right that
sense of that sense of yeah there's that
sense of as I stepped forward right the
what I was stepping on like roof goes
into the background but then becomes in
front of me yeah and that autopoietic it
yeah its spiral right that's a fantastic
connection yes it's so so Hermes the
messenger God languish right yeah
totally totally between the two right
dude always yeah so good this is so much
fun
so much fun Nikki John well thank you
God
it's like this sorry I don't want this
to sound self congratulatory but I want
to say trying to express reverence and
not be self congratulatory but this is
this is this kind of stuff yeah and then
you know and then the work I'm doing
with you and Peter and Jordan you know
it you know Chris right and like trying
to uh you know theorize about it but
never lose touch with the theoria or now
the fear Gia right and trying to get
them all like that's the most important
thing I'm doing it is what you said it
would be or saw that it is this gets
worked out it becomes you know the meta
psycho technology that shepherds and
curates and coordinates it feed it feeds
from but it also really feeds back into
all of the other practices I practice
and yenge and try to share with people
it's becoming so important to me yeah
it's like it's gathering I get this
sensor and I've been watching this with
you I've been watching this with you
because alright first when we first
talked I don't think this sense of
dialogue OHS was articulated yet in fact
you were I think you were I watched one
of your what are your first videos with
Chris when you were doing the series
yeah fact you're like yeah I'm trying to
work this thing out like that there's
something right if you were talking
about in terms of like the role of
religion right and like okay know
traditionally religion has taken this
that's become less and less viable so
how is it that we get these things
together is so interesting because it
you could tell you were like yeah it was
present as the struggle of it's missing
right oh yeah totally
um hang on one second I just might my
neighbor I have to close my door hanging
I got a little bit seasick radically
inspired by my neighbor's case but that
sense of you know that's uh there was
just that sense of it you were aware and
then it seems like dialo goes great and
in this thing just went Oh like
everything's just started to come
together and I'm getting this sense of
everything seems to be gathering itself
like and there's the logo right in the
face in the face of the Kairos but this
is what is singing to me right now most
pressingly but also beautifully in that
moment where Jordan said that to me
right so I had yeah very good I mean
good faith criticisms from my Jonathan
PI show and Paul van der clay and they
were like right and then and then when
Jordan said that and then I had that
moment of coming to something that
responded to them and but I could have
done anything on my own it had to be
like it was written
yeah yeah you know and then I started
you know I was already in dialogue with
you yes sorry and I started to see this
unfolding that's what it all came
together and I realized ah this this is
this is it
that was that that was you know that
that was that was the touchstone right
that started to reveal you know when he
should yeah we said the medicine
medicine technology of yeah they take
yeah the better technology and then
you're like the next day you're like I
think the thing that's circling and
maybe the thing that did it and then
that's been you have a conversation that
more people now are spontaneously this
is this is how you can tell when I think
you're really starting to get something
is one more people are starting to see
how these things could you know are they
can instantiate and exemplify and of or
a religion that's not a religion
so more people are saying I'm getting a
sense like you just did and again I'm
not the author of this we are not a
founder that's ridiculous idea this
sense right like yeah I'm getting a
sense of what this could be against now
it's gone from being an abstract
proposition or just some image it's
going to be no no no this this is this
is this is actually nation there's
something that is coming to earth right
now and so that that for me is like okay
I stopped but I'm a very careful
attention same thing I do with my
teaching my students when they start to
oh right then when they said to get the
gathering what you say it starts to take
on our life of its own
that's when it's a oh yeah yeah yeah
yeah I think you're exactly right this
is what is so exciting about right now
and again how did you this virtually how
to be how to be properly in relationship
with this excitement and this creativity
without losing touch with the suffering
and the distress happening and how to
keep them like in in proper proportion
that's what raffio eventually right
ratio was the Latin of logos right it's
trying that the proper proportion it was
that how they tried to get the sense of
were telling that to me is something
again I'm trying to get that kinship
that's your end ship with the logos yes
like I was thinking about like in a
certain sense you know how like
Aristotle would talk about like that the
that we think with the logos right like
that that that like it's we think with
it right but then there's a certain
point where it's like you think with it
but then at some point like it kinda
like the logos almost takes over right
in and there's a there's a point where
the logos thinks logos right well yeah
for me and that's what the musical
metaphors from Taoism are really helpful
because initially you're listening to
the
but then what starts to happen is
instead of you just sort of listening to
the music it's almost like you start to
becoming yet another instrument in the
orchestra right you get more castrated
why the music it's like just any other
instrument it goes back to you tuning
metaphor yeah yeah absolutely absolutely
in that sense to of you know and kind of
going back to the like towards the
beginning of our conversation just
bringing in that whole thing about just
wondering about this like and I don't
know if I understand his model
completely but that whole thing about
the justification what was what did he
call that when it comes out your friend
where it comes out of his system it's
great on Greeks that was he is really I
really like he's he's his ability to
think really clearly right about and
just take all of these things he's just
really I really I want it I want to
speak with him
well you should yeah yeah I wanted he's
gonna be on the he's been on the discord
server my destroy server like I said he
it Greg and I are going to do he he's
been sort of following all the stuff I'm
doing on consciousness right now and so
yeah I'm gonna have another session and
we're gonna do it about sort of
consciousness the problem consciousness
but we're gonna try and circle through
his work in mind easties he sees he sees
really deep connections with you know
the tree of knowledge that he's been
working on the attempt to get a synoptic
integration yeah
psychology and and the work I'm doing on
relevance realization is not the
integration and partners I mean what's
happening is that well it's reciprocal
opening between his work and I yeah but
yeah I mean he I mean there's been a
later book by Springer and Wilson
no not swear also -
uber and Mercier called the Ennead mark
reason where they basically argue for
that reason is properly is it's properly
they in property and process within
distributed cognition its biological not
monological opinion big tome of a book
the thing of it is Greg I mean there's
been a dispute between the them right
but it's clear to my mind after looking
at both great has absolutely precedent
he published way before they did his
argument it almost everything that they
have in their argument he has in his I
think the way to think about it is I
don't think they stole from him I don't
I don't have any good reason for saying
that I think they should properly give
him academic precedents yeah yeah sort
of held off on that I'm not happy with
that but what you've got is you've got
to and the similarities are so telling
I've got this powerful convergence of
all of this work being integrated
independently and then converging on
this idea hmm a great deserves real like
credit for this I'm not going to take
away from Sperber and Mercier the great
really deserves credit for this you know
for that you know reason is ultimately
dialogical in nature yeah yeah yeah
totally
in this sense of the sense of the
justification right the form of
justification justifies yes we are
versus precisely because yes we justify
and the justification is always
bi-directional we are always justifying
to others and justifying to ourselves
justifying ourselves to others but we're
also justifying others to us ray Trust
who is worthy yeah expressed right
totally now here's the thing about that
is I think there's a way
no wonder at what I thought what I
thought when I heard I was like well no
wonder people get nervous when they make
eye contact right like what there's this
phenomena really pointed out kind of
phenomena a lot logically it was like
well why is the human face always
confront me as an enigma
there's a sense in which that sense of
obligation yes I wonder if the
obligation is the obligation and
responsibility of justification on some
level of like and what also he said the
thing about the reverse engineering of
being able to speak I thought was a
great way of putting it of like oh yeah
yeah well you know I've been you know
talking about you know the design
stances the method
the methodology of cognitive science
appearing I mean as the way you and I do
here we're trying to reverse engineer
dialectic right yeah the historical
sources and the current practices yeah
yeah great was very much doing that I
mean there's something weird right
because when we if it's it's the face
right because animals have something
they have like if they're facing each
other there's there's there's threat
either a social threat of dominance or
threat of predation or even just
confrontation for sexual competition
right so there's animal threat you there
but then as you say in Lebanon spoil at
the call because we're persons in this
face of reason and justification there's
this extra thing that comes on top of it
there's there and then we and it was
really problematic is not only are both
happening we confuse them and like it
and we equivocate and we get that
stopped about those two different things
yeah you know I've heard this I've heard
people reliably say and apparently and
there's there's there's surveys and
polls to support this that the fear of
speaking in front of others is greater
than their fear of death yes right right
exactly because they could die their
personhood is is on trial yes and so
there's so this is what's really
interesting is like a couple of things
to look at Dyea logos in the context of
that right of one it seems like so so
there's there there's really toxic
versions of that right there's toxic
versions of that thing going on right
and that's that experience of shame and
humiliation and having to prove yourself
and you have to hide
or you have to be your justification is
defensive right in some way like it's
like being in the courtroom but I'm just
wondering about it's interesting to
think about is like well even from the
courtroom to the courtyard that's a
metaphor that's in my mind yeah to the
courtyard yes exactly exactly
so it what's interesting is like what is
it when you make that move right if we
what is the L or like that you could say
the elevation of that structure right
what is it that's getting justified or
maybe it's like the experience of
justice right but I think that says I
think instead of the project of
justifying ourselves yeah right I'm
gonna play with that word a little cuz
series right yeah how would you justify
the text where your right or left
justification I'm trying to come into
right relationship so that
intelligibility is maximized yeah so I
think of it
this is a metaphor that the
justification we're pursuing is not the
inferential defense of our proposition
yes it's again the proper alignment for
a movement it's coming into the right
relationship people oriented for that
what happens is I go from that the
attack mode is I've been thinking about
this for the rebel wisdom thing on
Saturday I go from attack to
amplification right if something so the
way I challenge you think about in order
for them to be flow I have to challenge
it yeah like this is it just oh I agree
with you we all love each other and
isn't this wonderful a messy rinoa it's
not that crap right right I have to
challenge you because if I don't put a
demand on you first of all you don't
have to respond and secondly you won't
get into the flow state there's no state
without demand
yeah if I attack you right then we're
into the courtroom but if I move to
amplification where I say well you're
talking about courage and I hear you
first of all I acknowledge I make sure
that I resonate with you when commit to
the process on the proposition and after
that I say but there's something about
courage that I love there's an aspect
that I didn't hear and what you're
saying yeah what do you think about this
what do you think about this and I try
to get you right back
I heard you saying this is this right is
there more you do this guy yeah and
there's your first help me unpack
remember the I'm cramping what I think
and then you'll say and we all do this
to each other one with reform and we'll
do the amplification we'll say but
there's a little bit I'm pretty words
but we usually enacted rather than being
it yeah yeah in words it's like but
here's another thing about courage that
I love that I didn't quite hear and what
you were saying but you do it in a Jaa's
way you say here's here's what I've
heard yeah and here's another can we can
be jazz our way from the one to the
other can we find the connecting flow so
we turn this is what I mean about moving
from the courtroom into the courtyard
here we challenge but the challenge is
not the challenge of attack the
challenge is the challenge of
amplification yeah I try I acknowledge
the suchness of what you said I
acknowledge in what you said when I have
not yet seen but then I challenge you
with the morning of what you might not
have yet seen right together
stereoscopically as we come to see
something more than we could see before
both of us together as the morning
the ground and the aspiration yes yes
totally Oh interesting
yeah interesting and that starts to get
into like where whereas normally like in
a courtroom it's all about like stress
it's it's like there's there's something
that you're trying to like win and the
voice in its established position yeah
yeah positional right exactly but this
is processional yeah one of the things
I'm going to ask people like when you
ask them to set an intention for Lexie
oh it's a set intention for reverence
yeah transformation and a commitment to
the process rather than to any position
right and not attack what we do is we
acknowledge we amplify and then we
anticipate right we're anticipating
getting to somewhere we couldn't get you
these are the things that I this is what
I'm trying this is what I'm going to
bring into the presentation on Saturdays
this is what I want to then get feedback
on and see it when you and I when the
four of us regular to keep trying to
reverse engineer dialectic right
absolutely beautiful and I have a client
as a matter of fact this is a great
place to complete yes my friend yeah
yeah beep send me the file and load you
up loaded first time your channel baekje
and then hopefully you'll get on the
discipline server right away okay great
what should we call this one you think
yeah what was coming out here was I
think what was coming out here is virtue
in three logos Barbossa X is the virtue
of India Villalobos and how virtue
reduces virtue how do you know the deuce
is virtue from us yes you did it and the
virtue that is drawn forth from us bingo
all right Oh take care of my friend this
was wonderful this is awesome I've
missed you
yeah yes yeah bye